# ARMAND REITZ

armandrtz@gmail.com / +1 408 479 7422 / armandreitz.com

Location: White Salmon, WA (open to relocation)

#### **SUMMARY**

Software developer with over three years of experience building front and backend systems for web and mobile applications. I'm a self-starter motivated to keep learning and improving existing skill sets. Experienced working with small teams utilizing agile methodologies. Single-handedly built and launched FourthTone, a subscription-based language learning SaaS platform.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **CREATOR**

FourthTone Mandarin - https://fourthtone.com December 2018 - Current

- Built a multi permission/role CMS. (React-admin)
- Built a client-facing web app. (React)
- Setup a payment and subscription system. (Stripe)
- Built a REST/Graphql API. (Node, Express, ApolloGraphql)
- Designed and implemented a relational database. (PostgreSQL)
- Deployed and maintained all services. (AWS EC2, NGINX, SSL/TLS, PM2, S3 static hosting, Github webhooks)
- Oversaw content creation, business operations, and business development.

#### RESIDENT FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

Coderbunker and LVMH - http://www.coderbunker.com January 2018 - May 2020

- Built an in store data collection tool. (React, Wechat Miniprogram, websockets)
- Built a sales rep curated sales channel. (Wechat Miniprogram)
- Built a campaign and customer management/tracking tool. (React, Wechat Miniprogram)
- Built data dashboards. (ECharts)
- Built a single sign on system (JWT and redirects).
- Built backend systems to support all the aforementioned. (Node, Graphal, REST)
- ETL of business and customer data. Extracted data from infoware databases, sftp servers, and csv files. Transformed data to remove errors, improve standardization, and increase usability. Loaded data into postgres and sqlite databases.

#### AP CHEMISTRY INSTRUCTOR

Beijing 101 Middle and High School September 2013 – July 2016

- Designed Introductory and Advanced Placement (AP) Chemistry courses.
- Taught students using an interactive and hands-on approach enabling them to score well above the global average on their AP exams.

## **TECHNOLOGIES**

## Core:

Javascript, Node, Express, REST, Graphql, AWS, NGINX, SSL/TLS, PostgreSQL, Git, Stripe, React, React-Native, Next, HTML, CSS, WeChat, Websockets, Styled Components

## Familiar:

Docker, Linux, Python

## **EDUCATION**

# **Bachelor of Science in Computer Science**

Oregon State University 09/2016 - 06/2018 Online

# **Bachelor of Science in Biology**

University of Oregon 09/2010 - 06/2012 Graduated Summa Cum Laude

# **Biology**

Montana State University 08/2008 - 06/2010 Transferred out to University of Oregon

## **LANGUAGES**

English (native)
Afrikaans (native)
Chinese (advanced)